# **NOLITA REGO**

Santa Clara, CA 95050 | (669) 388-1663 | nolitarego@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Software Engineer with strong coding skills (Java, JavaScript, Python), problem-solving abilities, possesses a deep understanding of technologies, teamwork, passion for innovation and continuous learning. A diverse background in database/cloud technology (SQL, NoSQL, Oracle, AWS) and web/mobile development (React, HTML, CSS, Vue.js, Angular, Flutter), excel in leading teams and driving innovative projects. Expertise also spans in Node.js, Flask, Git and REST API. Holds a track record of academic & professional achievements, positioning as a valuable contributor in software engineering endeavor.

# **EDUCATION**

Santa Clara University
Master of Science in Computer Science

Santa Clara, CA June 2023

University of Mumbai

Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

June 2021

Courses/Skills: Algorithms, Data Structures, Database Systems, Cloud Computing, Advanced Operating Systems, High Performance Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Distributed Systems, Microservices, Big Data, Computer Architecture, Object Oriented Programming, UI/UX Design, Computer Networks

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Applications Developer - SCU Frugal Innovation Hub, Santa Clara, CA

July 2023 - Present

- Spearheaded a team of 3 to develop a hybrid app for Belgian clients applying Flutter-Dart, local storage for offline functionality, and integrated Dialogflow chatbot alongside improved UX and browser service.
- Collaborated on launching compliance projects like ASL Facilitator for Uganda, Social Impact Integrator for Belgium, and testing and debugging issues in Java, JavaScript, SASS, Spring MVC, and AWS.
- Delivered high-quality solutions for quality assurance within budget, performed code changes/reviews, migrated applications, incorporated unit tests in Mockito to increase code coverage, and drove continuous improvement in coding standards.
- Steered end-to-end development and launch of 15 multilingual apps to track project success using KPIs, research, UX, multilingual support, communication, launch strategy, and performance analytics.
- Served as a Software Developer Intern, pioneering 100% cost-efficient software solutions for African and European clients, leading to full-time position.
- Engineered high-fidelity UI prototypes for interactive web/mobile applications utilizing Figma, React, and Flutter, integrated local storage capabilities, reviewed CI/CD pipelines, and offered constructive feedback to improve product quality.

# Software Development Intern - Mitchell International, Inc., San Diego, CA

June 2022 - September 2022

- Functioned in a 7-cohort team under the Auto Physical Damage unit for product development of Mitchell Estimating Solutions.
- Collaborated in NextGen Estimate to improve 90% of automated testing solutions by preparing test plans and cases, debugging complexity, fixing code smell, and blockers in C#, MSTest, Selenium, SonarQube, SonarLint for CI/CD code quality analysis.
- Developed cost estimation tool with machine learning algorithms, and React.js web framework, streamlining the assessment process, and enhancing accuracy in estimating automotive repair costs.
- Implemented car estimate auto-suggestion system with Trie data structure and distributed it across multiple shards.
- Collaborated with product managers and UX/UI designers to translate user requirements into intuitive software interfaces.
- Aided sibling team interns in building Java unit tests with JUnit, decreasing blockers and passing 82% of test cases.

# Mobile Application Developer Intern - FashionTV India, New Delhi, India

June 2020 - August 2020

- Performed in a cross-functional team to launch an online Wellness course platform, leveraging Flutter-SDK framework, 2-step Authentications, and Cloud Firestore for asynchronous data management and storage.
- Maintained an Admin section to manage various aspects including user data, course management, video processing, and implementing JWT tokens for login authentication. Additionally, utilized Postman for testing HTTP routes and endpoints.
- Tested on various mobile devices for latency check of the video player app using test cases for dynamic display resolutions.
- Designed highly decisive Adobe paradigms, increasing 85% of reliable user interfaces with further store deployment.

# **PROJECTS**

# Home-based Food Business Website - React.js, Tailwind CSS, Amazon SNS, AWS DynamoDB

• Devised a responsive web application using Tailwind CSS for effortless shopping cart functionality, integrated Amazon SNS for real-time updates, and utilized Fetch API to make HTTP requests to trigger the execution of AWS DynamoDB.

#### FlexPay - Payment and Transaction Application - JavaScript, OCI, Node.js, MongoDB, Python

• Engineered an e-commerce app in JavaScript, and Spring Boot, hosted on Oracle Cloud, integrated Microsoft Multi-factor Auth for security, and utilized Nginx, Express, and MongoDB Atlas for HTTP handling, server management, and Python database.

### Social Media Analysis for Mental Health Evaluation - Python, REST API, CNN, Flask, Firestore

• Developed a mental state analysis ecosystem using social media data and live REST API feeds with OAuth 2.0, utilized Flask-integrated CNN model, Twilio for notification/alerts, and DialogFlow for chatbot, achieving 89.28% test accuracy.

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, C, C#, C++, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Kotlin, XML
- Web/Mobile Technologies: Flutter, React Native, React.js, Redux, Angular, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Vue.js, Node.js, Flask
- Developer Tools: Figma, Linux, Git, Postman, Junit, Mural, Bitbucket, Confluence, DevOps, JSON, JQuery, AJAX, REST API, JIRA, Agile, Docker
- Databases/Cloud: SQL, PostgreSQL, PL/SQL, JDBC, AWS, OCI, NoSQL (Firebase, MongoDB)

## PUBLICATION, CERTIFICATIONS AND LEADERSHIP

- Technical Paper Publication: "Social Media Analysis for Mental Health Evaluation" IIRASET, Vol. 9 Issue IV, April 2021.
- Certifications: OCI Foundations Oracle; Meta Front-End Developer Meta; Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals Microsoft; AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud Native AWS; Generative AI: Introduction to Large Language Models LinkedIn; DeepLearning.AI Neural Network & Deep Learning
- Hackathons: Judge/Mentor: UnScript 2022 (National Level); Won Crescendo 2021; part of Smart India Hackathon 2020, Synergy 2019.
- Public Relations & Media Head TEDxCRCE; Marketing & Planning Department Students' Council CRCE.